<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on pnijhara&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://pnijhara.github.io/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on pnijhara&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 13:56:18 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pnijhara.github.io/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Methods and Status Code</title>
      <link>https://pnijhara.github.io/2020/08/http-methods-and-status-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 13:56:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pnijhara.github.io/2020/08/http-methods-and-status-code/</guid>
      <description>Before we begin coding, we must know basics about internet, specifically communication with API. We already covered our basics about APIs in the previous blog on &amp;ldquo;What is API, JSON or XML?&amp;quot;. It is now time to cover HTTP.
Communication between clients and server (which is our API) is done by HTTP(Hyper Text Transfer Protocol) requests and response. Every time client wants to perform some action on Database, it sends HTTP request to server and server in back respond by HTTP response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is an API, JSON or XML?</title>
      <link>https://pnijhara.github.io/2020/08/what-is-an-api-json-or-xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 10:00:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pnijhara.github.io/2020/08/what-is-an-api-json-or-xml/</guid>
      <description>API1 or the Application Programming interface is the middlepoint between App2 and data or it is a gateway to DataBase.
API governs the access point(s) for the server, that means instead of directly sending request to DataBase, API checks your identity and type of request and pass it through some logic filter and then reflect your request/change to the DataBase.
From the above diagram you can clearly see that, every request passes through a middleware(API) and then API performs some action/ checks validation and pass your request to DataBase to let it give you your desired response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcement: Python Backend blog series with FastAPI</title>
      <link>https://pnijhara.github.io/2020/08/announcement-python-backend-blog-series-with-fastapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 20:56:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pnijhara.github.io/2020/08/announcement-python-backend-blog-series-with-fastapi/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps more than any other language, Python has established itself as a solid tool to do almost anything. Where Python really shines, however, is in its various packages that extend the language into hundreds of use cases.
With this, this blog series will focus on building a strong and easily maintainable API with FastAPI framework of Python. I&amp;rsquo;ll be specifically focusing on best practices that every developer should must follow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>