<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on pnijhara&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://pnijhara.me/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on pnijhara&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 01:37:51 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pnijhara.me/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>https://pnijhara.me/2019/09/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 01:37:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pnijhara.me/2019/09/religion/</guid>
      <description>Recently I got the privilege to write an article for a non-governmental organisation named @lovenation_hme of Indian Institute of Law, Indore. The organisation aims to create unity among religions as being the responsible and literate citizens of India. The organisation also states that &amp;ldquo;India is ours and we are proud citizens of India&amp;rdquo;.
Article Religion is supposed to be the means of attaining peace but in practicality, in reality, today every religion has got a base of fundamentalism and involvement of terrorism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovered points associated with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://pnijhara.me/2019/08/uncovered-points-associated-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 01:09:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pnijhara.me/2019/08/uncovered-points-associated-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>In the last article, I tried to cover almost every point required for creating your blog. However, there are still some points left which remain uncovered in the previous section.
This article will cover those points which I feel are not covered in the official documentation or if covered are not much focussed in there quick start guide.
Point 1 Most of the time I read questions on the internet of people asking that even after creating or copying the config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create your own blog in 30 minutes using Hugo, a static site generator written in Go</title>
      <link>https://pnijhara.me/2019/08/create-your-own-blog-in-30-minutes-using-hugo-a-static-site-generator-written-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 17:18:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pnijhara.me/2019/08/create-your-own-blog-in-30-minutes-using-hugo-a-static-site-generator-written-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Do you know you can create your blog without any knowledge of content management system or actual knowledge of creating a website, setting it, styling it or improving it? Well, you can with the world’s fastest framework for building websites that is Hugo
Before going forward it is suggested that you must have an account on Github for hosting your blog.
Why Hugo?  Hugo is the fastest tool of its kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>https://pnijhara.me/2019/07/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 16:43:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pnijhara.me/2019/07/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to gift myself a new blog and here is the result :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog was created on Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>